<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/nfn/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/nfn/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-06-05T22:33:58+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/nfn/feed.xml</id><title type="html">NFN World News - Breaking News, World News, Entertainment</title><subtitle>NFN is a Nice Fake News site created by Russian hackers. We share only the most heart-warming and inspiring lies. And seed them by whatever means necessary…</subtitle><author><name>Oli Frost</name><email>mail@olifro.st</email></author><entry><title type="html">Man With Five Kidneys Donates Three</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/nfn/man-donates-three-kidneys/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Man With Five Kidneys Donates Three" /><published>2018-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/nfn/man-donates-three-kidneys</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/nfn/man-donates-three-kidneys/">&lt;p&gt;Jay Downing, 48, was born with a rare form of &lt;em&gt;supernumeracy&lt;/em&gt;, that gave him one and a half extra kidney pairs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The three extra kidneys were packed into his left and right abdominal cavities behind the two present in most people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr. Downing wasn’t even aware he had the condition until he went in for an x-ray in September last year, following a small hip injury.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On discovering the long waiting list in his local area, Downing quickly decided to give three of his spare
kidneys to donors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr. Downing said he would miss the shorter hangovers he had enjoyed for most of life, but was happy that he could give back something significant to his community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The operation took place in Denver, Colarado, and took less than four hours. The recipients included a mother of five, a 7 year old girl, and one pensioner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Downing said he had considered giving away a fourth kidney, but doctors claimed the operation carried too many risks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hospital recently awarded Downing with a bronze kidney statue as a tribute to his heroism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When receiving the award, Downing told the audience that he hoped his actions would inspire more to sign up for organ donation cards.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Oli Frost</name><email>mail@olifro.st</email></author><category term="Inspiring" /><summary type="html">Jay Downing, 48, was born with a rare form of supernumeracy, that gave him one and a half extra kidney pairs. The three extra kidneys were packed into his left and right abdominal cavities behind the two present in most people. Mr. Downing wasn’t even aware he had the condition until he went in for an x-ray in September last year, following a small hip injury. On discovering the long waiting list in his local area, Downing quickly decided to give three of his spare kidneys to donors. Mr. Downing said he would miss the shorter hangovers he had enjoyed for most of life, but was happy that he could give back something significant to his community. The operation took place in Denver, Colarado, and took less than four hours. The recipients included a mother of five, a 7 year old girl, and one pensioner. Downing said he had considered giving away a fourth kidney, but doctors claimed the operation carried too many risks. The hospital recently awarded Downing with a bronze kidney statue as a tribute to his heroism. When receiving the award, Downing told the audience that he hoped his actions would inspire more to sign up for organ donation cards.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/nfn/img/seven-kidney-man.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">People Are Using Their Phones Less</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/nfn/people-are-using-their-phones-less/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="People Are Using Their Phones Less" /><published>2018-03-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-03-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/nfn/people-are-using-their-phones-less</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/nfn/people-are-using-their-phones-less/">&lt;p&gt;A new study from the Department of Health, released today, has shown a 7% decline in Daily Average Phone Usage (DAPU) in the last year, against all expectations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is the first time numbers have fallen since the introduction of the first iPhone in 2007.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The researchers claim that an increased awareness of the health risks and social consequences of phone addiction, made widely known throughout the year, could explain the dip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, a study last year showed that people who didn’t use social media were 34% more satisfied with their social lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On average, each minute we spend on our phone will bring about 1 minute of usage for 3 other people picking up our emails and texts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This also means that not using our phones has an exponential effect on how much others use theirs too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But beyond the health impacts, Vanessa Bobinton, a sociologist at the research centre, thinks the change is part of a general shift in consumer preferences:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“People are craving more real, tangible experiences. The short term rewards of Likes and Comments are losing the allure that once held people to their phones”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the trend continues into next year, the researchers believe we’ll start to see knock-on effects for both the country’s economy and social well-being.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Oli Frost</name><email>mail@olifro.st</email></author><category term="Breakthroughs" /><summary type="html">A new study from the Department of Health, released today, has shown a 7% decline in Daily Average Phone Usage (DAPU) in the last year, against all expectations. It is the first time numbers have fallen since the introduction of the first iPhone in 2007. The researchers claim that an increased awareness of the health risks and social consequences of phone addiction, made widely known throughout the year, could explain the dip. For example, a study last year showed that people who didn’t use social media were 34% more satisfied with their social lives. On average, each minute we spend on our phone will bring about 1 minute of usage for 3 other people picking up our emails and texts. This also means that not using our phones has an exponential effect on how much others use theirs too. But beyond the health impacts, Vanessa Bobinton, a sociologist at the research centre, thinks the change is part of a general shift in consumer preferences: “People are craving more real, tangible experiences. The short term rewards of Likes and Comments are losing the allure that once held people to their phones”. If the trend continues into next year, the researchers believe we’ll start to see knock-on effects for both the country’s economy and social well-being.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/nfn/img/people-talking.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Blind Kittens See String For The First Time</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/nfn/lonely-blind-cats-see-string/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Blind Kittens See String For The First Time" /><published>2018-03-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-03-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/nfn/lonely-blind-cats-see-string</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/nfn/lonely-blind-cats-see-string/">&lt;p&gt;Missy, Tiger, and Coco were born with a genetic disease that left them blind at birth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unable to communicate with one another besides a pitiful “meow”, the kittens quickly became lonely and unhappy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But thanks to a new implant, doctors have been able to partially restore Missy, Tiger and Coco’s sight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To test the success of the operation, a piece of string was dangled in front of the kitten’s eyes upon awakening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The kittens were not only able to bat the string in front of them with their paws, but Missy even managed to pin down the string and claim it for herself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The test was also successful with shoe laces and blind cords.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cats’ owner says that since the operation the kittens have become less lonely, spending less time sleeping and more time chasing anything that moves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the implant is still a prototype, it could one day be rolled out to blind kittens across the country.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Oli Frost</name><email>mail@olifro.st</email></author><category term="Breakthroughs" /><summary type="html">Missy, Tiger, and Coco were born with a genetic disease that left them blind at birth. Unable to communicate with one another besides a pitiful “meow”, the kittens quickly became lonely and unhappy. But thanks to a new implant, doctors have been able to partially restore Missy, Tiger and Coco’s sight. To test the success of the operation, a piece of string was dangled in front of the kitten’s eyes upon awakening. The kittens were not only able to bat the string in front of them with their paws, but Missy even managed to pin down the string and claim it for herself. The test was also successful with shoe laces and blind cords. The cats’ owner says that since the operation the kittens have become less lonely, spending less time sleeping and more time chasing anything that moves. While the implant is still a prototype, it could one day be rolled out to blind kittens across the country.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/nfn/img/blind-cat.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Penguin Twins Reunited</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/nfn/penguin-twins-reunited/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Penguin Twins Reunited" /><published>2018-03-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-03-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/nfn/penguin-twins-reunited</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/nfn/penguin-twins-reunited/">&lt;p&gt;Shrimpy and Fishcakes, two emperor penguins, were separated shortly after birth following a mile-long iceberg split in 2010.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The two lived apart for seven years on opposite ends of Antarctica, until one eagle-eyed explorer for The Antarctica Survey noticed an unusual likeness between the colouring under their wings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After finding out the penguins were related through a DNA test, The Antarctica Survey arranged a visitation for the penguins by helicopter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Antarctica Survey claim that the two penguins both got on well, and shortly became friends. The two even shared similar interests, with both showing an inclination for the same kinds of seafood – especially krill.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The two penguins shared their birthday together before returning to their packs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The researchers plan to keep the penguins in touch with monthly Skype calls.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Oli Frost</name><email>mail@olifro.st</email></author><category term="Inspiring" /><summary type="html">Shrimpy and Fishcakes, two emperor penguins, were separated shortly after birth following a mile-long iceberg split in 2010. The two lived apart for seven years on opposite ends of Antarctica, until one eagle-eyed explorer for The Antarctica Survey noticed an unusual likeness between the colouring under their wings. After finding out the penguins were related through a DNA test, The Antarctica Survey arranged a visitation for the penguins by helicopter. The Antarctica Survey claim that the two penguins both got on well, and shortly became friends. The two even shared similar interests, with both showing an inclination for the same kinds of seafood – especially krill. The two penguins shared their birthday together before returning to their packs. The researchers plan to keep the penguins in touch with monthly Skype calls.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/nfn/img/penguin-twins.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">People Who Recycle Live Longer</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/nfn/people-who-recycle-live-longer/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="People Who Recycle Live Longer" /><published>2018-03-02T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-03-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/nfn/people-who-recycle-live-longer</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/nfn/people-who-recycle-live-longer/">&lt;p&gt;Last year it was shown that 7/10 people do not know which items should go in the recycling bin and 9/10 had never made efforts to find out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But a new study by mental health charity Mind has found that recycling comes not only with benefits for the planet, but for personal health as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In particular, it was found that the ritual of sorting recycling had almost the same psychological benefits as two minutes meditation or mindfulness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the past few years studies have proliferated linking these benefits with longer life by mitigating the impact of stress on our bodies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While sorting plastics from cardboard may not sound like the most interesting of tasks, the study claims that it is precisely this boredom that allows our mind to reach a more relaxed state.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The charity says that in the next few years recycling could even be offered as a new form of therapy for those suffering from small to mild anxiety symptoms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While personal sorting may be enough for most, the report goes as far as to claim that weekly volunteering at a local recycling centre could extend life by as much 6-8 years.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Oli Frost</name><email>mail@olifro.st</email></author><category term="Being" /><category term="Well" /><summary type="html">Last year it was shown that 7/10 people do not know which items should go in the recycling bin and 9/10 had never made efforts to find out. But a new study by mental health charity Mind has found that recycling comes not only with benefits for the planet, but for personal health as well. In particular, it was found that the ritual of sorting recycling had almost the same psychological benefits as two minutes meditation or mindfulness. In the past few years studies have proliferated linking these benefits with longer life by mitigating the impact of stress on our bodies. While sorting plastics from cardboard may not sound like the most interesting of tasks, the study claims that it is precisely this boredom that allows our mind to reach a more relaxed state. The charity says that in the next few years recycling could even be offered as a new form of therapy for those suffering from small to mild anxiety symptoms. While personal sorting may be enough for most, the report goes as far as to claim that weekly volunteering at a local recycling centre could extend life by as much 6-8 years.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/nfn/img/recycle.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Big-Nosed Monkeys Get Nosejobs</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/nfn/big-nosed-monkeys-get-nosejobs/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Big-Nosed Monkeys Get Nosejobs" /><published>2018-03-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-03-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/nfn/big-nosed-monkeys-get-nosejobs</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/nfn/big-nosed-monkeys-get-nosejobs/">&lt;p&gt;Big-nosed monkeys are endemic to the Southeast Asian island of Borneo, and live amongst normal monkeys.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Early last year, conservationists noticed that big-nosed monkeys suffered from social exclusion and were less likely to find a mate than their smaller nosed counterparts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the findings were made public, the local population stepped in to help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a fundraising drive the village was able to pay for the monkeys to undergo minor plastic surgery that would reduce the size of the nose area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since the operation many of the monkeys have been able to return to their packs and find new mates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One monkey, Imala, gave birth to her first child last week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Locals who knew the pack well reported that Imala’s mate would likely have been “out of her league” before the operation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A competition has been started in the nearest village to name the new baby monkey, with more babies expected
by the end of the year.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Oli Frost</name><email>mail@olifro.st</email></author><category term="Inspiring" /><summary type="html">Big-nosed monkeys are endemic to the Southeast Asian island of Borneo, and live amongst normal monkeys.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/nfn/img/monkey-nose.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Ugly People Get Promoted Faster, Study Shows</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/nfn/people-who-are-ugly-get-promoted-faster/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Ugly People Get Promoted Faster, Study Shows" /><published>2018-02-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-02-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/nfn/people-who-are-ugly-get-promoted-faster</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/nfn/people-who-are-ugly-get-promoted-faster/">&lt;p&gt;In 2012 a poll showed that 74% of people believe their more attractive peers would climb faster in their careers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But a new study, released yesterday by the United Workers Union, now offers evidence to the contrary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The study plotted workers attractiveness on a scale of 1-10 against their pay grade.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The results showed that less attractive people had on average a 23% higher wage, split evenly across men and women after taking into account other factors, such as gender pay disparity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The study also tracked the average rate of promotion, finding that less attractive people were promoted on average ever 1.8 years, compared to 2.1 for more attractive people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While there is little historical data on the matter, the researchers believe that changing attitudes in the workplace have created a shift towards talent as a focus for promotion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The researcher further speculated that less attractive people have a greater motivation to succeed because of their lack of natural “advantages” in their looks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The study is set to continue over the next ten years.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Oli Frost</name><email>mail@olifro.st</email></author><category term="Well-being" /><summary type="html">In 2012 a poll showed that 74% of people believe their more attractive peers would climb faster in their careers.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/nfn/img/climbing.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Watching Netflix Makes You Smarter, Funnier, And Better In Bed</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/nfn/new-study-netflix-users/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Watching Netflix Makes You Smarter, Funnier, And Better In Bed" /><published>2018-02-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-02-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/nfn/new-study-netflix-users</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/nfn/new-study-netflix-users/">&lt;p&gt;A new report published by the Royal Institute of Health &amp;amp; Wellness has revealed the positive impacts watching Netflix has on our health and well-being.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The study was based on a census of 10,000 millennials over the course of two years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While many saw binge-watching their favourite shows as a guilty pleasure that “rots their brain”, the report claims Netflix offers more benefits to our well being than reading or going to university.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The paper informing the study claims to have taken inspiration from ancient Greek philosophy’s ideas on “mimesis”, or imitation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“In watching Netflix, millennials learn to imitate the skills and personalities they see. As most characters in online shows are smarter, funnier, and better in bed than normal people, this presents an opportunity for learning”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The results that follow are mostly unsurprisingly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Viewers that watched House of Cards became better at politics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Viewers that watched Mad Men became better at picking up the opposite sex.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And viewers that watched Sherlock generally became better at solving crimes and other detective work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As Netflix is watched after work and all day at weekends by many millennials, the report is welcome news.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The full report is set to be published at the end of the month along with a companion book that pairs learning interests with shows on the streaming service.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Oli Frost</name><email>mail@olifro.st</email></author><category term="Well-being" /><summary type="html">A new report published by the Royal Institute of Health &amp;amp; Wellness has revealed the positive impacts watching Netflix has on our health and well-being. The study was based on a census of 10,000 millennials over the course of two years. While many saw binge-watching their favourite shows as a guilty pleasure that “rots their brain”, the report claims Netflix offers more benefits to our well being than reading or going to university. The paper informing the study claims to have taken inspiration from ancient Greek philosophy’s ideas on “mimesis”, or imitation. “In watching Netflix, millennials learn to imitate the skills and personalities they see. As most characters in online shows are smarter, funnier, and better in bed than normal people, this presents an opportunity for learning” The results that follow are mostly unsurprisingly. Viewers that watched House of Cards became better at politics. Viewers that watched Mad Men became better at picking up the opposite sex. And viewers that watched Sherlock generally became better at solving crimes and other detective work. As Netflix is watched after work and all day at weekends by many millennials, the report is welcome news. The full report is set to be published at the end of the month along with a companion book that pairs learning interests with shows on the streaming service.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/nfn/img/netflix.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">George R. R. Martin To Release 2 Books Tomorrow</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/nfn/george-r-r-martin-release/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="George R. R. Martin To Release 2 Books Tomorrow" /><published>2018-02-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-02-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/nfn/george-r-r-martin-release</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/nfn/george-r-r-martin-release/">&lt;p&gt;Fans of fantasy novel series A Song of Ice and Fire (the basis of the HBO series Game of Thrones) have had a long wait between instalments of the series.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was a six-year gap between the fourth volume, A Feast for Crows (2005), and the fifth volume, A Dance with Dragons (2011), and the fifth volume The Winds of Winter has moved slowly since.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In April 2018, Martin claimed that the book would not be published in 2018.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, to the surprise of fans, G.R.R.M’s publisher Bantam Spectra today announced that he will release not one, but two new books tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first is the long awaited The Winds of Winter, which will be accompanied by a short prologue book set before the first novel: A Glimpse of Spring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Martin claimed he purposefully lowered expectations for the book’s release in order to take pressure off the writing process and give fans a surprise for its eventual launch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The books will be on sale online from tomorrow in the UK and US, with other translations to arrive in the following month.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Oli Frost</name><email>mail@olifro.st</email></author><category term="Inspiring" /><summary type="html">Fans of fantasy novel series A Song of Ice and Fire (the basis of the HBO series Game of Thrones) have had a long wait between instalments of the series. There was a six-year gap between the fourth volume, A Feast for Crows (2005), and the fifth volume, A Dance with Dragons (2011), and the fifth volume The Winds of Winter has moved slowly since. In April 2018, Martin claimed that the book would not be published in 2018. However, to the surprise of fans, G.R.R.M’s publisher Bantam Spectra today announced that he will release not one, but two new books tomorrow. The first is the long awaited The Winds of Winter, which will be accompanied by a short prologue book set before the first novel: A Glimpse of Spring. Martin claimed he purposefully lowered expectations for the book’s release in order to take pressure off the writing process and give fans a surprise for its eventual launch. The books will be on sale online from tomorrow in the UK and US, with other translations to arrive in the following month.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/nfn/img/grrm.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Heroic Sheep Saves Lamb From Cliff Face</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/nfn/heroic-sheep-saves-lamb/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Heroic Sheep Saves Lamb From Cliff Face" /><published>2018-02-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-02-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/nfn/heroic-sheep-saves-lamb</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/nfn/heroic-sheep-saves-lamb/">&lt;p&gt;Euan, a sheep from Dorset, England, became a local hero yesterday, after saving one of his lambs from a cliff face.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While running from the farm’s sheep dog, a lamb from the flock came off the cliff and was left “hanging by its teeth”, according to Dan Conyngham-Hynes, a local who witnessed the event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The lamb was faced with a drop of approximately 210ft, before Euan came to the rescue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Euan was able to lift the lamb by the wool on his back and pull him to safety, where he was met with open arms by Graham Hughes, his shepard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A local vet arrived on the scene only a few hours later, who announced the lamb only had mild shock related symptoms and could return to its flock by the end of the week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following the incident the local authorities said the incident had served as a “wake up call” and announced plans to do more to tackle coastal erosion in the area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A crowdfund to improve and repair the fencing around the cliff face is already 312% funded at the time of writing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The additional funds will cover the cost of a wooden sheep statue to be erected by the cliff face.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Oli Frost</name><email>mail@olifro.st</email></author><category term="Inspiring" /><summary type="html">Euan, a sheep from Dorset, England, became a local hero yesterday, after saving one of his lambs from a cliff face. While running from the farm’s sheep dog, a lamb from the flock came off the cliff and was left “hanging by its teeth”, according to Dan Conyngham-Hynes, a local who witnessed the event. The lamb was faced with a drop of approximately 210ft, before Euan came to the rescue. Euan was able to lift the lamb by the wool on his back and pull him to safety, where he was met with open arms by Graham Hughes, his shepard. A local vet arrived on the scene only a few hours later, who announced the lamb only had mild shock related symptoms and could return to its flock by the end of the week. Following the incident the local authorities said the incident had served as a “wake up call” and announced plans to do more to tackle coastal erosion in the area. A crowdfund to improve and repair the fencing around the cliff face is already 312% funded at the time of writing. The additional funds will cover the cost of a wooden sheep statue to be erected by the cliff face.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/nfn/img/heroic-sheep.jpg" /></entry></feed>